

Researcher & Technologist

jamesdavidmoffet.com

jim@jamesdavidmoffet.com

in jamesdavidmoffet

about

As a researcher and technologist, I am obsessed with understanding the mechanism by which technology delivers us into an alternative future. As a design researcher, I learned to temper this obsession, harnessing critical theory and a range of ethnographic research techniques that help to resist the internal inertia that new technologies tend to assert and to instead apply user-centered, systems-level thinking to the awesome challenge of improving people's lives.

education

2016 - 2018

Harvard University Graduate School of Design

Master's degree, Design Technology Studies

SKIIS

Design Research
UI/UX Design
R, SPSS, Python, Torch
Software Engineering
Hardware Engineering
Public Speaking
Project Management
Product Design

work experience

OutVote.io & Commit.vote

2017 - Present Cambridge, MA, USA Founder / Director of UX
 Founded civic tech startup COMM!T to test efficacy of peer-enforced smart contracts in driving civic participation.
 Joined forces w/ OutVote civic networking app post-election 2017.

Civic Tech Fellow

Summer 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA UX Researcher / Technologist
 Developed civic technology for the City
 of Cambridge, focusing on easy to
 deploy open source citizen analytics
 apps and consulting with GolNVO on UX
 research for new MA SNAP application.

MIT Community Innovators Lab

2016 - 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA Research Manager
 Managed a democratic capacity
 mapping project for the MIT Community
 Innovators lab. Oversaw research labor
 as well as designed and engineered a
 democratic capacity mapping and organizational partnership tool.

Fulbright Fellow

2015 - 2016 Budapest, HU Design Researcher / Lecturer
Researched community fablabs at the
Center for Media, Data and Society at
CEU in Budapest. Also piloted OpenLab
public design workshops teaching UXR,
interface design and hardware/software
prototyping for public projects.

SEIU

2009 - 2014 Portland, OR, USA Senior Product Manager
 Led design and development of in-house financial-member system handling 25M records, 50 corp. partners, \$5M revenue.